brandverity.com 2018-09-03

# Privacy Policy | BrandVerity

## Your Privacy and BrandVerity.com

BrandVerity provides subscription and contract brand monitoring services. We know that you care about how the Personal Data (as defined below) we receive about you is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. This Privacy Policy describes BrandVerity’s privacy practices in relation to information that we collect through the website operated by us from which you are accessing this Privacy Policy (the “Site”). Our data protection practices are compliant with GDPR as we understand its laws and implications.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that BrandVerity does not own or control, or to individuals that BrandVerity does not employ or manage. This Privacy Policy also does not apply to information that we receive or handle on behalf of our subscribers in our role as a service provider. Such information is governed by the terms of the applicable subscription services agreement, rather than this Privacy Policy. 

If, after reading through this policy carefully, you still have questions, please reach out to us at privacy@brandverity.com. You may also request a copy of this Privacy Policy by contacting us at privacy@brandverity.com. 

## What Types of Information Does BrandVerity Collect?

  * Personal Data. “Personal Data” is information that, directly or indirectly, identifies you or another individual and which may include: name, title, company name, job function, expertise, postal address, telephone number, email address, browser and device information (including IP Address), and information collected through cookies and other similar technologies. If you submit any Personal Data relating to other people to us or to our service providers in connection with the Site, you represent that you have the authority to do so and to permit us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  * Other Information. “Other Information” is any information that does not and cannot be used to reveal your identity or that of another individual, such as information which has been fully and permanently anonymized and aggregated. We use this information to facilitate our operation of the Site and for other purposes described below.

## How Does BrandVerity Collect Information? 

We and our service providers collect Personal Data and Other Information in a variety of ways, including:

  * Through the Site: We collect information through the Site, e.g., when you request a free trial or demo, register for a webinar, contact us, subscribe to our email newsletter, download content (e.g. whitepapers), or register to use our Site.
  * Offline: We collect information from you offline, such as when you attend one of our events, during phone calls with sales representatives, or when you contact a BrandVerity representative.
  * Through You: BrandVerity collects information such as your location or your preferred means of communication when you voluntarily provide it. Unless combined with Personal Data, this information does not personally identify you or any other user of the Site.
  * Information From Other Sources: In order to enhance our ability to provide relevant marketing, offers, and services to you, we may obtain information about you from other sources, such as public databases, joint marketing partners, social media platforms, as well as from other third parties.
  * Through Your Browser or Device: Certain information is collected by most browsers or automatically through your device, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, Internet browser type and version, and the name and version of the Site (such as the Apps) you are using. Your “IP Address” is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP). An IP Address may be identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever you access the Site, along with the time of the visit and the page(s) that you visited. Collecting IP Addresses is standard practice and is done automatically by many websites, applications and other services. BrandVerity uses IP Addresses to calculate usage levels of the Site, help diagnose problems with its servers, administer the Site, identify security threats and for monitoring the regions from which you navigate to BrandVerity’s Site.
  * Through Cookies and Other Similar Technologies: "Cookies" include commonly used pieces of information in the form of small files that are placed on an individual’s device to enable the individual to more easily communicate and interact with the Site. When you visit our Site, we may send one or more cookies to your device. They enable us to store information about your device which helps us, amongst other things, to provide you with a good experience when you browse our Site and enhance the level of services and functions provided. We also use third parties to serve advertisements on other websites that may be of interest to you, based on information collected about your use of our Site and other websites. To do so, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie or similar on your browser. BrandVerity recognizes automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, which may include ‘do not track’ instructions. 
  * By Aggregating Information: Aggregated Personal Data does not personally identify you or any other user of the Site (for example, we may aggregate Personal Data to calculate the percentage of our users who have a particular telephone area code).

## How Does BrandVerity Use Personal Data? 

We use Personal Data:

  * To present our Site and its content to you.
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us.
  * To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it.
  * To provide you with notices about your subscriptions to the Services, including expiration and renewal notices.
  * To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection.
  * To notify you about changes to our Site or any products or services we offer or provide though it.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features on our Site.
  * In any other way we may describe when you provide the information.
  * For any other purpose with your consent.

We never sell your Personal Data or provide it to others for their marketing purposes.

Our legal basis for collecting and using the Personal Data described above will depend on the Personal Data concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. We will collect and use your Personal Data where the processing is in our legitimate business interests, such as for direct marketing and sales of BrandVerity’s Services. Our legal basis for processing Personal Data in certain circumstances will also be based on your consent to do so, a contractual basis (such as when we need the Personal Data to perform a contract with you or in order to enter into a contract with you) or for legitimate interests (such as to enforce mailing-list opt-outs, account audit history or perform security forensics). In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect Personal Data from you.

If we ask you to provide Personal Data to comply with a legal requirement or to enter into a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your Personal Data is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your Personal Data).

## Does BrandVerity Disclose Personal Data?

We may collect and disclose anonymous and aggregated information about our users and subscribers, and other information that does not identify any individual, without restriction for the purposes of product research, to improve our Services, and for other commercial purposes.

We may disclose Personal Data that we collect or you provide as described in this Privacy Policy:

  * To our subsidiaries and affiliates.
  * To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it. For example, if you give us an email address to use the "Violation Email" feature of our Site, we will transmit the contents of that email and your email address to the recipients.
  * For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information.
  * With your consent.

We may also disclose your Personal Data:

  * To comply with any court order, law or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request.
  * To enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes.
  * If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of BrandVerity, our customers or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

## What Are My Choices About How BrandVerity Uses and Discloses My Information?

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the Personal Data you provide to us. We have created mechanisms to provide you with the following control over your information:

  * **Tracking Technologies and Advertising.** You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. To learn how you can manage your Flash cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings page on Adobe's website. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of the Site may then be inaccessible or not function properly.
  * **Promotional Offers from BrandVerity.** If we have sent you a promotional email, you may send us a return email asking to be omitted from future email distributions. This opt out does not apply to information provided to BrandVerity as a result of a product purchase or trial.

## How Does BrandVerity Secure Personal Data About Me?

We have implemented measures designed to secure your Personal Data from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration and disclosure. We use the Transport Layer Security (TLS, also known as SSL) protocol for the exchange of data between our Site and your device. Further, all pages on the Site use the TLS protocol’s encryption and certificates.

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of our Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of the Site like message boards. The information you share in public areas may be viewed by any user of the Site.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee the security of your Personal Data transmitted to our Site or via our Services. Any transmission of Personal Data is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Site or via the Services.

## For How Long Will BrandVerity Retain My Personal Data?

We will retain your Personal Data for a period of time consistent with the original purpose of collection, including to pursue our legitimate business interests, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce applicable agreements.

## How Can I Opt Out?

If you’d like to opt out of all marketing communications from us, you can do so [here](https://resources.brandverity.com/hs/manage-preferences/unsubscribe-simple). You can change the alerting information you receive [here](https://app.brandverity.com/monitor/setup/email/).

To opt out of targeted advertising generally, please see the information on the [DAA opt-out site](http://www.aboutads.info/), the [NAI opt-out site](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/), or the [EDAA opt-out site](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) if you’re in Europe.

You may also send us an email at privacy@brandverity.com to request correction or deletion of any Personal Data that you have provided to us.

## Sensitive Information

We ask that you not send us or disclose any sensitive Personal Data (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, sexual orientation, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, biometrics or genetic characteristics, criminal background, or trade union membership) on or through the Site or via other means.

## Children Under the Age of 13

Our Site is not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any information to or on the Site. We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on the Site or on or through any of its features/register on the Site, make any purchases through the Site, use any of the interactive or public comment features of the Site or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, email address or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received Personal Data from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at privacy@brandverity.com.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

BrandVerity may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. The “Last Updated” date at the bottom of this page indicates when this Privacy Policy was last revised. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy on the Site.

## Contact Information

To ask questions or comment about this Privacy Policy and our privacy practices, contact us at privacy@brandverity.com.

Last Updated: May 24, 2018
